# **FARAN MASOOD PEERZADA**

Bahawalpur, Punjab, Pakistan, +92-3005078036, faranpeerzada253@gmail.com

## RESEARCH INTEREST

My primary field of research interest is Artificial Intelligence (AI). Within AI, I am interested in problems related to probabilistic modeling, Machine Learning, and Remote Sensing, and their interdisciplinary applications to Precision Agriculture. I have found the applications in Precision Agriculture to be exciting not only because of their practical value but also as an inspiration for new types of problems that prompt the development of new theories and algorithms that have not been investigated before.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Working as Python developer on Upwork

October 2022 - Continue

Centre of Agriculture and Bioscience International (CABI) Regional Research Centre, Rawalpindi, Pakistan

Worked as a Consultant for IT and Digital Tool development under Project titled "Plantwise Plus" July 2021 - October 2022

October 2020 - June 2021

May 2019 - September 2020

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Designing and developing analysis systems to extract information from large-scale data.
- Applying data mining techniques to Harmonize Plantwise eclinic data.
- Implementing Machine learning techniques on Plantwise data to achieve desired results.
- Worked as Machine Learning Expert on a Project titled "Mapping and Estimating Parthenium hysterophorus using Unmanned Aerial Vehicle Imagery"

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Data Collection using drone and multispectral sensor.
- Stitching UAV data to acquire mosaics using OpenCV and Python.
- Calibrating Hi-resolution Multispectral Sensor.
- Labeling and processing data using Machine learning algorithms.
- Worked as Research Assistant on a Project "Remote Sensing
   Parthenium in Pakistan"

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Collecting aerial data using the multispectral Hawkpi sensor.
- Developing field maps for high-resolution data collection using a DJI Matrice 100.
- Creating a pipeline for stitching multispectral data using OpenCV and Python.
- Processing data using machine learning algorithms.
- June 2017 July 2018

- ❖ National Internship Program, Pakistan
  - Teaching Assistantship

### **EDUCATION**

 National University of Sciences and Technology, College of E&ME, Islamabad, Pakistan

#### September 2017 – November 2020

#### **MS Mechatronics Engineering**

- Area of concentration: Machine Learning, Computer Vision
- Thesis: Evaluation of High-Resolution Airborne Imagery for Mapping Invasive Weeds in Crops
- Advisor: Dr. Wagar Shahid Qureshi
- CGPA: 3.65/4.00
- The Islamia University of Bahawalpur, University College of Engineering and Technology, Bahawalpur, Pakistan

# **BSc Computer Systems Engineering**

- Area of concentration: Image Processing and Robotics
- FYP project: Human Presence-Based Auto Switching of Room Appliances to Save Energy
- CGPA: 3.46/4.0

**September 2012 – July 2016** 

# **SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

- Programming Languages: Python, C++, JavaScript,
- Programming Tools: Visual Studio Code, PyCharm, Anaconda, Git, Adobe Dream viewer
- Image Stitching Tools: WebODM, Zephyr Aerial
- Python Packages: Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, OpenCV, Keras, Matplotlib, Seaborn, PyTorch, TensorFlow, Tableau, Selenium, BeautifulSoup, OpenAI, Langchain
- Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Bootstrap
- Web servers: AWS
- Databases: MySQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL
- Framework: Django, Laravel
- Drones: Phantom series, Mavic Series, Matrice 100
- Remote Sensing Tools: QGIS and ArcGIS
- Publication Tools: LaTeX, Visio, MS Office

# **Certifications**

- CCNA (Routing and Switching) from CORVIT Systems, Lahore, Pakistan.
- Linux (RHCSA) from CORVIT Systems, Lahore, Pakistan.
- Web Development using PHP from Aptech Bahawalpur, Pakistan

# **Course Projects**

- M.Sc. Course Project
  - Smart touch pen for smart devices
- B.Sc. Course Project
  - RDBMS Web-based tutorial using HTML, CSS, PHP
  - Course work record-keeping system using C++

# Languages

- English [Proficient]
- Urdu [Native]

# References

- Dr. Waqar Shahid Qureshi, Assistant Professor
   National University of Sciences and Technology (NUST), Islamabad Pakistan waqar.shahid@alumni.ait.asia
- Rene Breton, Professor of Astrophysics
   Jodrell Bank Centre for Astrophysics, University of Manchester, Manchester, United Kingdom rene.breton@manchester.ac.uk
- Dr. Joseph Fennell, Postdoctoral Research Associate
   Jodrell Bank Centre for Astrophysics, University of Manchester, Manchester, United Kingdom joseph.fennell@manchester.ac.uk